-- Usagi Drop Episode 06 --
Done?
Umm, yeah.
It's really out of focus!
Rin-chan, Kouki, stand together!
Okay!
Kouki-kun.
Get ready!
Elementary
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Elementary
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Alright, I'll take one of you with Rin-chan now.
Oh, no thanks.
Go on! She'll grow up in the blink of an eye.
You have to hold on to these moments!
Okay.
Elementary
School
Entrance
Ceremony
Daikichi-san, don't look so stiff!
Presented by:
Taka Fansubs
Not again!
Rin! How many times do I have to tell you not to leave my side like that?!
Okay.
You're a young lady now, so start acting like one!
Say something else!
Daikichi, can we buy this for snacks?
Snacks?!
I just thought it looked good.
Have you ever had cereal before?
Nope.
Do you think it's too big for me?
No, I don't mind buying it.
But you normally have that for breakfast.
I can eat candy with rice?
Well, let's see...
It looks like candy, but you can have it as a meal.
It goes with milk.
Wanna have it for breakfast tomorrow?
Yeah! I do!
Will you too?
I'm fine. It doesn't fill me up.
Put the cereal in here.
Okay.
You're no good at that, Daikichi.
My hands are too slippery.
You're just like Grandpa.
Be quiet!
Keep trying then!
Daikichi, let's walk where the cherry blossoms are.
Okay.
They're everywhere!
It's warm out, that's why.
Isn't it big?
It's in full bloom.
What do you say we plant something to
commemorate your new start in elementary school?
"Commemorate"?
It's like creating a memory.
You and the tree would grow together every year.
I have one myself, you know.
At home?
At my parents' home.
When I was born, they planted a fragrant olive.
And when my sister was born, they planted a tea olive.
Are fragrant olives the ones that smell nice?
Yup.
I don't know what a tea olive is.
Well, the tea olive doesn't really have a nice smell or many flowers,
which is why my sister would complain and try to steal the ones from my tree.
When I offered to trade, she would just scream and say she didn't want hand-me-downs.
Hold on, those aren't very fond memories.
Why am I trying to repeat it with Rin?
Well, if we do end up getting one, how about a pretty one or one with lots of flowers?
Or maybe one that bears fruit.
I want a plum tree!
A plum tree?
Yeah, a plum tree!
I have the seeds for it!
You want to plant them?
I can eat all the plums I want then!
Only if they're ripe.
I was thinking we could plant a tree that's about as tall as you are.
No plum tree?
Well, a tree doesn't grow as fast as a morning glory.
It's like they say, "Good things
will come to those who wait."
"So don't be impatient!"
You really are Grandpa's kid, aren't you?
What about plum trees?
I'm not really sure.
What'll you do if it takes ten years?
I can wait.
I have a feeling you'll prefer fancy desserts by then.
At least that's what I imagine.
Daikichi, hurry!
If we don't hurry, we won't be able to eat them for a long time!
Okay, okay.
Is this enough?
Yeah.
Any deeper and it won't be able to sprout.
Okay.
You're a spitting image of Grandpa, you know.
I hope it sprouts soon!
Me too.
Rin, do you know what a ninja is?
Yeah, Kouki-kun says he's going to become one.
Well, it's said that ninjas jump over a hemp tree every day,
and while the tree gradually grows taller,
they're able to jump to extraordinary heights.
Why don't you try that with your plum tree?
Okay!
Like that.
Was that right?
Yup.
How tall does a plum tree grow?
Will it reach our roof?
Umm, I guess so.
Let's go inside.
Ten more!
I wonder if it'll sprout tomorrow.
I don't think so.
Got everything?
Yeah.
My teacher said someone from home has to look over my schedule.
I have to?
They didn't have this when I was your age.
She's right. It says I have to sign.
A fire?
I think it's the police.
A crime?
I'm not sure.
Daikichi, put this whistle on my knapsack.
Rin.
If a stranger tries to talk to you, blow really hard into the whistle, okay?
Okay.
Then run into the first house you see!
Or a store!
Okay!
Rin, school!
Daikichi, get up!
I'll be late!
Right.
Thank you for this meal.
Don't forget the milk.
Can I eat some of it just like this?
Yeah, I guess.
Dogs eat this too!
That's dog food!
It's made for dogs.
Really?
Really!
Humans aren't supposed to eat dog food!
Don't look so sad.
Do you like it?
Yeah! It's yummy.
My rice balls are still number one though!
They sure are good.
Your phone's ringing.
Right.
Good morning!
I'm so sorry! Kouki was so excited he just couldn't wait!
Oh, that's okay.
It's no problem.
Rin-chan!
Okay.
Kouki-kun's here!
Rin-chan!
He's here.
Hey.
Kouki-kun, you're covered with seeds!
Did you walk through the forest or something?
I'm not an animal!
And what happened to your hair?
Rin, go get a comb.
Okay.
Now your knapsack's got marks all over it.
You used that stick to scrape home walls, didn't you?
Can you read my mind?!
I knew it right away!
Is it because you used to do it too?
Rin, go and get ready!
Okay.
What are you looking at?
I'm leaving!
Wait!
Hold on!
What's wrong?!
Kouki-kun, you shouldn't blow it when nothing's wrong!
Kouki-kun!
Hey!
Stop that!
No one will come when you're really in trouble now!
Okay?
Yeah.
Alright, get going.
Bye!
Look out for cars!
Okay!
Kouki-kun!
Let's go through here!
We shouldn't go another way.
We're not! It's a shortcut.
Ninjas always take shortcuts!
Geez...
It keeps zig-zagging!
Yup!
Kouki-kun, hurry up!
It's not a shortcut otherwise!
Not now!
Kouki-kun!
He sure is a handful.
Isn't he?
Well, I guess all boys are like that.
Daikichi.
All I said about ninja training was jumping over trees, right?
Fine!
Hey, that plum tree is because I'm starting school, right?
Right.
But you got a fragrant olive when you were born, so it's not the same, right?
I guess I don't have something like a fragrant olive.
She sure is smart.
Is her mother the type to plant a tree?
I wonder if there's one at Grandpa's house.
True, Grandpa would do that.
But you don't remember seeing one, do you?
No.
And now Grandpa's gone...
If I don't know about it, no one does, right?
I never should have told her about my fragrant olive.
Daikichi, your elbows!
Right! Sorry!
Damn it.
I never thought I'd see you again.
I was thinking the exact same thing.
This is from her school entrance ceremony.
Thank you.
Huh? A tree for Rin?
Wait, there is one!
Really?
Or there was one...
Why can't you remember?
Souichi-san was the one who planted it.
Grandpa did?
I want to move that tree to my place.
What kind is it?
A small one.
I mean, what variety is it?
And where is it?
Well, it's still small, and its branches are thin...
It's here.
Are you really a manga artist?
I don't draw many maps!
Which way's north?
North?
Well, if the sun rises in the west...
Wrong! It rises in the east!
Don't worry about the direction.
Please just draw the street that's in front of the house.
Right, of course.
I have some work to do, so I'll be leaving.
Thank you for the dessert.
Sorry for calling you when you're busy.
I wonder if I have a tree?
Grandpa must have planted something for you, Rin-chan.
That's what I believe.
And even if he didn't, we'll just plant a new one to celebrate your entrance into school.
A six year old tree.
Okay.
Would you like to see Daikichi's tree?
Yeah, I do!
It's so big!
That's because it's thirty years old, just like Daikichi.
Daikichi grew up as well!
It's a fragrant olive, right?
That's right. Good job!
Daikichi told me.
And this one is Kazumi's.
A tea olive?
Yes.
Do you remember seeing a big tree in Grandpa's backyard?
Yeah!
That's my tea olive.
Wow!
This tree...
Grandpa planted it when I was born.
So, you have the same kind of tree as Kazumi?
That's right.
I always used to measure my
height against it when I was young.
I treasured it so much that I did the same for my children.
Was that a tea olive?
Did Daikichi measure his height too?
Of course!
Long before you and I first met...
Is that...
Its leaves are the same!
It's a six year old fragrant olive, just like mine.
All done.
Oh, no!
What is it?
I don't think I can jump over this.
Me neither.
It's hard to believe we didn't even know about Rin six months ago.
It really is.
Daikichi, we'll miss the train!
Coming!
See you.
I'll walk you to the station.
Still...
Long before you and I first met...
you were already following in our footsteps.
Daikichi!
What's wrong?!
What is it?!
There's a weird old man outside!
Wait, Kouki-kun. That guy is...
What?!
Wait, Daikichi...
Where's the old fart?!
Listen to me, you guys!
That's our neighbor, Matsui-san!
He's not a weird old man!
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry...
Don't be. I think I gave him a fright when I suddenly dropped by.
My apologies.
Please, it was extremely rude of us.
Well then, take care.
Bye!
Thank you.
You took Rin with you when you ran from him.
What? But he was wrong about him!
I'll worry a little less when Kouki's with you.
What do you mean "a little"?!
I mean "a little"!
You're still a little kid!
I am not!
We're going to be late.